Guide to the Yale Miscellaneous Manuscripts Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Alphabetical, Series I
  - Lee, William H.: diary, 1866 (Box 12, Folder 459)
  - Leffingwell, William: ALS to Henry D. Bulkley, photostat of cash account, constitution of Yale Alumni Association: Transferred to Leffingwell Family Papers Mss 320, 1827-1828, undated (Box 12, Folder 460)
  - Leonard, Apollos: astronomy notes and notes on the calendar, 1764 (Box 12, Folder 461)
  - Levy, Edward G.: TLS to James Babb, 1959 (Box 12, Folder 462)
  - Levy, Irving: poem about Yale University, 1946 (Box 12, Folder 462)
  - Lewis, Alonzo N.: manuscript "Life is a Tale that is Told", 1878 (Box 12, Folder 464)
  - Lewis, Charlton M.: ALS to his father, Charlton T. Lewis, 1882 (Box 12, Folder 465)
  - Lewis, Charlton T.: Transferred to Charlton T. Lewis Papers, Mss 981 (Box 12, Folder 465a)
  - Lewis, Dudley: correspondence concerning M.A. course, 1916 (Box 12, Folder 466)
  - Lewis, Thomas: notebook: "A Collection of Observations, Extracts from Theological Discourses, Lectures, etc.", ALS to his parents, 1796-1797 (Box 12, Folder 466a)
  - Lindbergh, Charles A.: typescript of a speech delivered at Yale: Transferred to Yale in WW2 Coll Mss 1212 8/85 (Box 12, Folder 467)
  - Lindsley, C. Purdy: TLS from Edward D. Adams, 1905 (Box 12, Folder 468)
  - Lindsley, Philip: ALS to the President and Professors of Yale College recommending J.R. Eakin, 1842 (Box 12, Folder 469)
  - Linsley, James H.: ALS to Messrs. Durrie and Peck with enclosure: Transferred to James H. Linsley Papers, 1841 (Box 12, Folder 470)
  - Linsley, Timothy: ALS to Miron Barrett, [1843?] (Box 12, Folder 471)
  - Little, Walter H.: ALS to the Registrar of Yale University, 1949 (Box 12, Folder 472)
  - Locke, Samuel: ALS to President Daggett with transcript, 1771 (Box 12, Folder 473)
  - Lohmann, Carl A.: notes on the adoption of Yale blue, with silk sample, 1941 (Box 12, Folder 474)
  - Loomis, James L.: TLS to Charles Seymour, 1943 (Box 12, Folder 475)
  - Lord, Daniel: ALS to Professor Larned, 1852 (Box 12, Folder 476)
  - Lord, Peter: correspondence with transcripts, 1826-1829 (Box 12, Folder 477)
  - Lyman, Chester S.: letters on the history of student magazines at Yale, letters from his Hawaiian Pupils, 1847-1849, 1876-1877 (Box 12, Folder 478)
  - Lyman, Joseph (1749-1828): ALS to Henry Davis: Transferred to Misc MSS L, 1800 (Box 12, Folder 479)
  - Lyman, Joseph: receipt, 1819 (Box 12, Folder 480)
  - Lyman, Jonathan H.: ALS to his father, Joseph Lyman: Transferred to Misc MSS L, 1801 (Box 12, Folder 481)
  - Lyman, Soloman: ALS to Lucretia Williams, 1820 (Box 12, Folder 482)
  - McCabe, Donald C.: typewritten article about Yale-in-China and note from one of the bachelors, 1941 (Box 12, Folder 483)
  - McCall, S.W.: typewritten copy of pages from Dodge lecture, 1915 (Box 12, Folder 484)
  - McChain, James: ALS to William Humphrey, 1836 (Box 12, Folder 485)
  - McCormick, Nelson W.: papers concerning the American Field Artillery School of Instruction, 1917-1921 (Box 12, Folder 486)
  - McCrea, S. Harkness: oil landscape painting, undated (Box 12, Folder 487)
  - McCurdy, Charles J.: ALS to L.S. Foster: Transferred to Misc MSS M, 1825 (Box 12, Folder 488)
  - McGregor, Donald R.: photostat of manuscript song "Magic Christmas": Transferred to Misc MSS M, 1967 (Box 12, Folder 489)
  - McKinney, William A.: ALS to "My Dear Prof", manuscript of "The History of the Cardiff Giant Hoax", 1875, undated (Box 12, Folder 490)
  - McLaughlin, Edward T.: typescript "The Little Foresters", undated (Box 12, Folder 491)
  - Machen, E.C.: TLS to Franklin B. Dexter, 1900 (Box 13, Folder 492)
  - Mallery, Garrick: ALS to J. Dunbar Crugh, 1842 (Box 12, Folder 493)
  - Maltby, Erastus: ALS to his sister-in-law, Mrs. Charlotte A. Maltby, 1818 (Box 12, Folder 494)
  - Manice, Edward: 2 ALS to Ruth Bainton and notes on Jerome Davis' Peace, War and You, 1953 (Box 12, Folder 495)
  - Manigault, Charles: ALS to Louis Manigault, 1845 (Box 13, Folder 496)
  - Mann, Parallas A.C.: transcript of letter to his sister, 1852 (Box 13, Folder 497)
  - March, Daniel: ALS to Rev. Henry Darling, [1870?] (Box 13, Folder 498)
  - Marsh, Ebenezer G.: photostat of invitation to preach from Richard Lush, K.K. Van Rensselaer, and Sanders Lansing, 1803 (Box 13, Folder 499)
  - Martin, Newell: TLS to Hotchkiss, 1897 (Box 13, Folder 500)
  - Mason, Ira M.: 3 short story typescripts, undated (Box 13, Folder 501)
  - Mason, Jeremiah: typed extracts from his autobiography: Transferred to Jeremiah Mason Papers Mss No. 347 10/82, 1873 (Box 13, Folder 502)
  - Massie, Patrick C.: ALS to "Dear Blatchley", 1848 (Box 13, Folder 503)
  - Maxwell, Sylvester: disputes written as Yale student, diary, notes on law, 1795-1798 (Box 13, Folder 504)
  - May, Mark A.: 3 reports on the Institute of Human Relations at Yale, 1970-1972 (Box 13, Folder 505)
  - Meeks, Carroll Louis V.: Transferred to Theodore Sizer Papers, Mss 453 (Box 13, Folder 506)
  - Meigs, Josiah: "Catalogue of the Articles in the Museum of Yale College by J. Meigs, Keeper of the Museum", 1796 (Box 13, Folder 507)
  - Merrill, Arthur B.: 6 ALS from Harold Smith, 1869-1870 (Box 13, Folder 508)
  - Merrill, Payson: ALS to W.C. Duyckinck, 1871 (Box 13, Folder 509)
  - Merriam, G. & C.: 12 ALS from various Yale professors to Messrs. G. & C. Merriam concerning Webster's dictionary, 1834-1848 (Box 13, Folder 510)
  - Merritt, Alfred K.: ALS to William Lyon Phelps, 1942 (Box 13, Folder 511)
  - Merwin, Walter Lee: college bills, exam papers and memorabilia, 1876-1878, undated (Box 13, Folder 512)
  - Metzdorf, Robert F.: correspondence and other material concerning the Van Sinderen Prize, 1957-1959 (Box 13, Folder 513)
  - Mills, John Y.: ALS to Sylvester W. Turner, 1837 (Box 13, Folder 514)
  - Mills, Samuel: diary, 1772-1791 (Box 13, Folder 515)
  - Minnigerode, Meade: TL to Mr. Krug, 1932 (Box 13, Folder 516)
  - Minor, Matthew: compositions and disputations written while at Yale College, 1799-1808 (Box 13, Folder 517)
  - Mitchell, Donald G.: ALS to Mr. Stokes, 1901 (Box 13, Folder 518)
  - Mitchell, John W.: ALS to Charles Ives, 1847 (Box 13, Folder 519)
  - Mixter, George: manuscript of the address he delivered at Yale commencement, 1836 (Box 13, Folder 520)
  - Mixter, William Gilbert: 5 ALS to William G. Mixter from various correspondents, 1875-1892 (Box 13, Folder 521)
  - Moore, E.H.: manuscript, "The Division of a Place into Polygons by n unlimited straight lines", 1885 (Box 13, Folder 522)
  - Moore, Franklin: typewritten copies of 4 letters to Justin Whiting, 1863 (Box 13, Folder 533)
  - Moore, Nathaniel S.: manuscript poem "Song", undated (Box 13, Folder 534)
  - Morgan, Christopher: ALS to Nahum Capen, 1850 (Box 13, Folder 535)
  - Morris, Henry G.: ALS to the President of Yale College, 1896 (Box 13, Folder 536)
  - Morse, Bennett W.: expense book, diary, 1848-1850, 1848-1852 (Box 13, Folder 537)
  - Mory's Association: 5 receipted bills to Lucius B. Barbour, typewritten notice to members, 1899-1900, 1917 (Box 13, Folder 538)
  - Moses, Robert: Transferred to Hollon Farr Papers, Mss 910 (Box 13, Folder 539)
  - Moss, Reuben: ALS to "Dear Friend", 1786 (Box 13, Folder 540)
  - Mulford, Daniel: "A Satire" by Daniel Mulford, article by Clarence M. Day about Daniel Mulford, "The Thinking of a Young Man at the Turn of the Nineteenth Century", 1805, undated (Box 13, Folder 541)
  - Mumford, George S.: manuscript memorandum on the Mumford family genealogy, 1894 (Box 13, Folder 542)
  - Munn, John [attributed author]: "The trials of a literary life," valedictory address possibly delivered at Monson Academy by John Munn (Box 13, Folder 543)
  - Munson, Stephen: signature on flyleaf from a book, on same leaf signature of Benjamin Trumbull, 1727, 1757 (Box 13, Folder 544)
  - Nehru, Jawaharlal: greeting to Yale University, 1957 (Box 14, Folder 545)
  - Nettleton, Edward P.: statistics of the Brothers of Unity, undated (Box 14, Folder 546)
  - Newbold, Michael T.: letters to his parents and sister, tuition bill, 1862-1864 (Box 14, Folder 547)
  - Newton, Hubert A.: ALS to Jonathan Hiller, ALS to Mrs. Hiller from Elias Loomis: Transferred to Hiller Family papers Mss 280, 1861-1862 (Box 14, Folder 548)
  - Newton, Jesse: letters to his parents, brother and sister, ALS from his father to Baxter Dickinson and the Senior Class of Yale College, receipt, 1815 (Box 14, Folder 549)
  - Niemeyer, John H.: ALS to Ellen Bartlett, 1929 (Box 14, Folder 550)
  - Niles, John: photostatic copies of letters to Sylvester Dana, 1798 (Box 14, Folder 551)
  - Noble, William Henry: letter of introduction for George W. Francis, 1870 (Box 14, Folder 552)
  - Nooney, James: material relating to his position as professor of mathematics in the Navy, proclamation appointing Nooney California state agent for the French Exposition, 1839-1840, 1866 (Box 14, Folder 553)
  - North, Simeon: ALS to Messrs. Bennett and Bright, 1836 (Box 14, Folder 554)
  - Norton, Edward: handwritten manuscript, "Journal of a Sophomore's Day at Yale," read before the Linonian Society, 1840 (Box 14, Folder 555)
  - Norton, James S.: correspondence, poems, memorial tribute, speech, 1864-1897 (Box 14, Folder 556)
  - Nott, Samuel: 2 ALS from Jeremiah Day, 1824 (Box 14, Folder 557)
  - Noyes, Edward S.: letters from various correspondents, 1923-1936 (Box 14, Folder 558)
  - Noyes, Joseph: Transferred to the Kingsley Papers, Mss 604 (Box 14, Folder 559)
  - Nyabongo, Akiki K.: correspondence and photograph, 1957 (Box 14, Folder 560)
  - Oates, P.A.: ALS to Mr. Kinsell, 1904 (Box 14, Folder 561)
  - O'Brien, Robert W.: translations in verse: "Ad Maecenatem Carmen XXIX, Lib. III", undated (Box 14, Folder 562)
  - Odell, Charles F.: ALS to Charles Seymour, Yale College receipts, news clipping, 1882-1892, 1939-1941 (Box 14, Folder 563)
  - Oko, Adolph S.: typescript of "The Yale Jewish Exhibit in its Cultural Aspects", 1940 (Box 14, Folder 564)
  - Olcott, George: correspondence, 1801-1803 (Box 14, Folder 565)
  - Olds, Irving: typescript of speech delivered at Yale Alumni luncheon, photographs and speeches pertaining to Olds as conferee of honorary degrees, Yale honorary degree (1956), 1948, 1954-1959 (Box 14, Folder 566)
  - Olmstead, Hawley: ALS to J.L. Kingsley recommending William L. Hinman for entrance to Yale, 1849 (Box 14, Folder 567)
  - Osborn, Isaac H.: licence to practice law, 1811-1816 (Box 14, Folder 568)
  - Osborn, Norris G.: TLS to Charles Bliss from Robert Corwin concerning a bust of Osborn, 1928 (Box 14, Folder 569)
  - Osborne, A.O.: ALS to his father, Amos Osborne, 1832 (Box 14, Folder 570)
  - Osgood, Charles H.: 3 ALS to Radcliffe Hicks, 1860-1862 (Box 14, Folder 571)
  - Ostrander, H. J.: list of contributors to the Old Library, 1925 (Box 14, Folder 572)
  - Oviatt, Edwin: TLS to George Dudley Seymour concerning Nathan Hale, ANS to unnamed correspondent, 1936, undated (Box 14, Folder 573)
  - Packard, Lewis R.: ALS to C.E. Norton, manuscript on "The Senses", diploma, travel documents, 1881 (Box 14, Folder 574)
  - Palmer, Alexander: ALS from W.S. Silsby, 1878 (Box 14, Folder 575)
  - Palmer, Charles R.: Transferred to the Palmer Family Papers, Mss 383 (Box 14, Folder 576)
  - Palmer, R.: Transferred to the Palmer Family Papers, Mss 383 (Box 14, Folder 577)
  - Panizzi, Sir Anthony: ALS to the Secretary, Yale College, 1863 (Box 14, Folder 578)
  - Parish, Roswell: letters from various Yale correspondents, 1861-1863 (Box 14, Folder 579)
  - Parker, Horatio W.: ALS to Sadie F. Rosenthal, 1898 (Box 14, Folder 580)
  - Parker, John A.: Transferred to Natural Science Manuscript Group, Mss 583 (Box 14, Folder 581)
  - Parker, Julian N.: ALS to Dr. Brigham, 1865 (Box 14, Folder 582)
  - Parmelee, Dubois D.: ALS to Charles A. Seely, 1865 (Box 14, Folder 583)
  - Parsons, Francis: letter informing him of his election to Phi Beta Kappa, 1815 (Box 14, Folder 584)
  - Parsons, Isaac: 3 ALS to Dr. Jonathan Knight, 1851-1864 (Box 14, Folder 585)
  - Paterson, Andrew B.: ALS to his aunt with transcript, 1835 (Box 14, Folder 586)
  - Patton, John: Transferred to F.B. Dexter Papers, Mss 712 (Box 14, Folder 587)
  - Peabody, Francis Stuyvesant: ALS to his father, Francis B. Peabody, 1880 (Box 14, Folder 588)
  - Pearl, Joshua F.: 3 leaves from the family Bible, autograph of classmate, announcement of his daughter's death, business blotter, 1869, 1890, undated (Box 14, Folder 589)
  - Pearce, Cyrus: poem "The Yaliad" and other related material, 1801 (Box 14, Folder 590)
  - Peck, Graham: cartoon from the Yale Alumni Weekly, undated (Box 14, Folder 591)
  - Peck, Tracy: TLS from Anson Phelps Stokes regarding honorary degree recipients, other lists relating to honorary degree recipients, 1901-1905 (Box 14, Folder 592)
  - Pendleton, Leonard: ALS to his father, 1865 (Box 14, Folder 593)
  - Percivil, James M.: two watercolor sketches of him, undated (Box 14, Folder 594)
  - Perkins, Alfred E.: correspondence and compositions, 1825-1830 (Box 14, Folder 595)
  - Perkins, Frederick B.: ALS to Dr. Holbrook, 1872 (Box 14, Folder 596)
  - Perkins, Jacob: ALS to John Rockwell, 1837 (Box 14, Folder 597)
  - Perkins, John: ALS to unidentified correspondent, 1855 (Box 14, Folder 598)
  - Perkins, Samuel H.: notebook, 1817 (Box 14, Folder 599)
  - Perkins, Thomas C.: 2 ALS to Norman Bull and Emily Perkins, 1817-1818 (Box 14, Folder 600)
  - Perrin, Lavalette: "John Smalley, D.D.," handwritten manuscript, with ALS from Perrin to the Rev. Asa Bullard: Transferred to Misc MSS P, 1868, undated (Box 15, Folder 601)
  - Peters, J.A.: ALS to unidentified correspondent, undated (Box 15, Folder 602)
  - Peters, John: 7 ALS to Henry B. Sargent, 1932-1933 (Box 15, Folder 603)
  - Pettingell, Amos: correspondence and other material concerning the monument marking his grave, 1940, undated (Box 15, Folder 604)
  - Pettingell, John H.: ALS to J.L. Parker, 1851 (Box 15, Folder 605)
  - Phelps, Arthur S.: letters to Arthur S. Phelps and to other family members concerning Phelps, memorial for Arthur L. Shipman, 1920, 1938, undated (Box 15, Folder 606)
  - Phelps, Sylvanus D.: 2 ALS from his mother, Mercy P. Collins, 1896 (Box 15, Folder 607)
  - Phelps, William W.: AN regretting inability to dine with the Clover Club, 1885 (Box 15, Folder 608)
  - Phi Gamma Delta: correspondence and printed matter, 1910-1920, undated (Box 15, Folder 609)
  - Phillips, Andrew W.: TLS to Professor Sumner: Transferred to Sumner Papers, MSS 291, 1896 (Box 15, Folder 610)
  - Phoenix Bank. Hartford, Conn.: list of stockholders in New Haven, 1836 (Box 15, Folder 611)
  - Pierce, Frederick E.: carbon of typewritten poem "The Flapper and the Chaperone", undated (Box 15, Folder 612)
  - Pierpont, John: ANS to Hon. Richard Fletcher, 3 ALS to William C. Gilman, ALS to White, Potter, & White, 1840-1841 (Box 15, Folder 613)
  - Pierpont, Mrs. John: genealogical material concerning Pierpont family, undated (Box 15, Folder 614)
  - Pierson, William S.: manuscript play (no title), undated (Box 15, Folder 615)
  - Pinckney, John T.: Transferred to Boardman Family Papers, Mss 89 (Box 15, Folder 616)
  - Pirsonn, Louis V.: ALS to Prof. Niemeyer, 1901 (Box 15, Folder 617)
  - Pitkin, Timothy: ALS to Jeremiah Day, 1832 (Box 15, Folder 618)
  - Poole, W.F.: ALS (photostatic copy) to L.E. Jones, 1881 (Box 15, Folder 619)
  - Porter, Edward C.: manuscript of his first sermon with note to his father on last sheet, manuscript of "Class Poem", 1858, undated (Box 15, Folder 620)
  - Porter, John A.: ALS to Augustus R. Street, ALS to unidentified correspondent: Transferred to Misc MSS P, 1860, undated (Box 15, Folder 621)
  - Porter, Noah: Transferred to Noah Porter Papers, Mss 1131 (Box 15, Folder 622)
  - Porter, R.: manuscript poem "The Association", undated (Box 15, Folder 623)
  - Post, Martin M.: TLS to Dr. [Erwin R.] Goodenough, 1949 (Box 15, Folder 624)
  - Pound, Louise: TLS to Dr. R[obert] J. Menner, 1922 (Box 15, Folder 625)
  - Pratt, Julius H.: ALS to Col. William Bull, 1842 (Box 15, Folder 626)
  - Pratt, Nathaniel A.: ALS from N.S. Pratt and L. Bacon to the Alumni of Yale College at the Theological Seminary in Andover, 1819 (Box 15, Folder 627)
  - Rabinowitz, Louis M.: remarks in Hebrew by Louis Sachs in presenting portrait of Louis M. Rabinowitz, 1953 (Box 15, Folder 628)
  - Radtke, Leonard B.: "Is There Room for Better Forestry in the United States," carbon of typewritten manuscript, 1939 (Box 15, Folder 629)
  - Rand, Kenneth: manuscript poems and themes, 1912, undated (Box 15, Folder 630)
  - Randall, John F.: tuition bill, ALS from Theodore D. Woolsey concerning Randall, 1862 (Box 15, Folder 631)
  - Ray, Simon: correspondence concerning Ray, 1947 (Box 15, Folder 632)
  - Raymond, Robert: 2 ALS to his son, Edward A. Raymond, 1841, 1842 (Box 15, Folder 633)
  - Reed, Edward B.: list of contributors to Wrexham Memorial, receipt, memorabilia: Transferred to Edward Bliss Reed Papers, Mss 412 1/83 NR, 1901-1902, undated (Box 15, Folder 634)
  - Reeve, Nathaniel: photostatic copy of sermon outline by Reeve; carbon of typewritten manuscript by Horace D. Reeve, "Nathaniel Reeve, Preacher and Patriot"; correspondence concerning Reeve, 1903, 1954, undated (Box 15, Folder 635)
  - Reid, Jared: 8 ALS to Samuel D. Cowles, 1841-1847 (Box 15, Folder 636)
  - Rice, Luther: photostatic copies of correspondence, 1815-1818 (Box 15, Folder 637)
  - Richardson, Lewis Bradford: typewritten signed poem, "Bear-Wallow Hill"; TLS to English Department, Yale University; carbon of TLS to Lewis Bradford Richardson, [ca. 1910], 1950 (Box 15, Folder 638)
  - Rider, Henry S.: ALS to William Lyon Phelps concerning William Lampson, 1940 (Box 15, Folder 639)
  - Ripley, Alfred L.: ALS to George Parmly Day: Transferred to George P. Day Papers, Mss 174, 1940 (Box 15, Folder 640)
  - Ritch, Thomas G.: Latin exercise book, undated (Box 15, Folder 641)
  - Ritter, Thomas: ALS to "My Posterity", 1824 (Box 15, Folder 642)
  - Robert, Ellis H.: ALS to Publishers Globe, 1872 (Box 15, Folder 643)
  - Rockwell, Julius: ALS to W. Bullard Preston, ALS to Edwin Percy Whipple, ALS to Globe office, 1850-1855 (Box 15, Folder 644)
  - No. 135: Woolley, Edgar Montillion, (1888-1963): An acting version of Christopher Marlowe's Tamburlaine the Great, by Edgar Montillion Woolley and Stephen Vincent Benét. Cover title in ms., followed by the printed text of the drama, cut and mounted on loose sheets numbered as pages, with ms. annotations and revisions, 1954 (Box 15, Folder 645)
  - Robinson, Lucius F.: verse written while an undergraduate (25 pieces), 2 essays and a printed copy of his class poem, 1843, undated (Box 15, Folder 646)
  - Robinson, William E.: journal kept as a passenger on the Ganges, Liverpool to New York, when he first arrived in the U.S. from Ireland; ALS to Hamilton Fish; 21 ALS addressed to him, largely relating to Psi Upsilon fraternity; 3 receipts for college bills, 1836, 1853, 1837-1877, 1851 (Box 15, Folder 647)
  - Rogers, Alexander P.: "The Technique of Speed Rowing," typewritten manuscript, 1940 (Box 16, Folder 648)
  - Rollins, Carl P.: "Fifty Books of 1923, Catalogue of an exhibition of...", TLS to Carl P. Rollins enclosing TLS from Paul A. Bennett to George Parmly Day, index to John W. Barber's wood blocks, 1923, 1949, undated (Box 16, Folder 649)
  - Rom, Roy C.: "Fifty Years of Yale Rowing," typewritten manuscript, signed by author, undated (Box 16, Folder 650)
  - Romaine, Hunter H.: three compositions, undated (Box 16, Folder 651)
  - Rosenthal, Warner A.: ALS to "Dear Editor," Davenport College, Yale University, 1951 (Box 16, Folder 652)
  - Rosseter, Asher: Latin and logic exercise books, 1902 (Box 16, Folder 653)
  - Ruggles, Charles J.: 4 ALS to his uncle, Charles H. Ruggles, 1837-1839 (Box 16, Folder 654)
  - Ruggles, Samuel B.: ALS concerning George B, Strong, 1860 (Box 16, Folder 655)
  - Russell, John S.: Transferred to Elihu Yale Papers, Mss 566 (Box 16, Folder 656)
  - Russell Trust: list of pamphlets in library, treasurer's records, building contract, 1858-1855, undated (Box 16, Folder 657)
  - Sackett, William H.: photostatic copies of 4 letters to his parents: Transferred to Misc MSS S, 1799-1803 (Box 16, Folder 658)
  - Safford, George B.: Yale memorabilia, 1848-1852 (Box 16, Folder 659)
  - Sage, Leveritt H.: three compositions, undated (Box 16, Folder 660)
  - Salisbury, Frederick S.: ALS to "Dear Charley", 1863 (Box 16, Folder 661)
  - Salter, Richard: ALS to Stephen Williams, 1747/1748 (Box 16, Folder 662)
  - Saltonstall, Gurdon: biographical material: Transferred to Misc MSS S, undated (Box 16, Folder 663)
  - Saltonstall, Leverett: ALS to unidentified correspondent, 1841 (Box 16, Folder 664)
  - Sammis, Augustus: 9 ALS to his father, 2 ALS to his mother, 5 ALS to his sister, ALS to Sammis from Thomas B. Kent, 1840-1850 (Box 16, Folder 665)
  - Sanford, Horace M.: signed typewritten manuscript, "Yale's Oldest Building", undated (Box 16, Folder 666)
  - Saurer, David Lee:
    See box 18
  - Sawyer, Charles H.: typewritten manuscript of speech, "The Arts in a Liberal Education", 1948 (Box 16, Folder 667)
  - Sawyer, E.: Yale Cruiser Fund subscriptions and accounts, 1898-1900 (Box 16, Folder 668)
  - Schieffelin, Edward L.: typewritten manuscript, "David Bushnell and the First American Submarine", undated (Box 16, Folder 669)
  - Schlesinger, Frank: typewritten manuscripts of addresses delivered at memorial services for him, 1943 (Box 16, Folder 670)
  - Scott, Lauren S.: 21 manuscript essays and orations written while an undergraduate, 1846-1847, undated (Box 16, Folder 671)
  - Scranton, William W.: ALS to E.L. Richards, 1869 (Box 16, Folder 672)
  - Scripture, E.W.: ALS to Henry L. Twain, 1907 (Box 16, Folder 673)
  - Scully, Vincent J.: typewritten manuscript of lecture on architecture at Yale and proposal for film adaptation of lecture, undated (Box 16, Folder 674)
  - Seabury, Joseph B.: Transferred to Warren B. Seabury Papers, Mss 790 (Box 16, Folder 675)
  - Seccombe, John [attributed author]: Father Abbey's will [copy?], 1731 (Box 16, Folder 676)
  - Seymour, Charles: TLS to Edmund A. Prentis, 1946 (Box 16, Folder 677)
  - Seymour, D[avid] L.: ALS to Mr. Jones, 4 ALS to Greene C. Bronson, 1844, 1853 (Box 16, Folder 678)
  - Seymour, George D.: ALS to Miss Goe, 1928 (Box 16, Folder 679)
  - Seymour, Origen S.: 21 ALS to Charles L. Mills, mostly from Origen S. Seymour; ALS from Elizabeth (Day) Seymour, Thomas Waterman, 1825-1835, undated (Box 16, Folder 680)
  - Shannon, E.V.: "Precaution to be observed in the use of Gooch Crucibles"; "A Method for Determining Insoluble Silica, Antimony, Lead and Iron in One Weighing of Sample Antimonial Lead, Etc." (both carbons of typed manuscripts), undated (Box 16, Folder 681)
  - Sharp, George H.: 15 ALS to Severyn Bruyn; ALS to his uncle, P.G. Sharp, 1846-1848 (Box 16, Folder 682)
  - Shaw, Edwin C.: honorary inscription to Shaw, 1936 (Box 16, Folder 683)
  - Sheffield, Charles J.: 3 account books, 1855-1863, undated (Box 16, Folder 684)
  - Sheffield, George St. J.: correspondence and other material relating to Yale crew, 1876-1923 (Box 16, Folder 685)
  - Shepard, Forrest: TLS to Anne S. Pratt concerning an obituary record of Shepard, 1943 (Box 17, Folder 686)
  - Shepard, Lorrin A.: letters to family and others, 1919-1928 (Box 17, Folder 687)
    Scope and Contents